Yen-Cheng Liu

Mail: ycliu@gatech.edu Personal Page: Link

Education

Georgia Tech, Atlanta, GA

Ph.D. student, Machine Learning, GPA: 4.00/4.00

Aug. 2018 - Present

National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan

M.S., Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.19/4.30

Sep. 2015 - June 2017

National Chiao Tung University, Hsinchu, Taiwan

B.S., Electrical and Computer Engineering, GPA: 4.24/4.30 Sep. 2011 - June 2015

Research Summary

Machine learning (ML) applications require huge **foundation models** trained on vast **data** and **labels**. My research focuses on improving the **efficiency of model parameters**, **data**, **and label annotations** in training of large-scale machine learning models. Beyond these, I also worked on **efficient and robust inference**, which exploits communication techniques to exchange information across different ML models.

Experience

Meta Research

May 2022 - Dec. 2022

Research Intern

Collaborators: Kunpeng Li, Xiaoliang Dai, Chih-Yao Ma, Zijian He, Peter Vajda

- Developing parameter-efficient multi-task adaptation of foundation models [NeurIPS'22]
- Reducing 90% trainable parameters while maintaining multi-task accuracy gains

Facebook Research

May 2021 - Dec. 2021

Research Intern

Collaborators: Xiaoliang Dai, Chih-Yao Ma, Zijian He, Ross Girshick

- Improving object detectors with large-scale unconstrained unlabeled images [ECCV'22]
- Improving object localization in semi-supervised manner with SoTA results [CVPR'22]

Facebook Research

May 2020 - Aug. 2020

 $Research\ Intern$

Collaborators: Chih-Yao Ma, Zijian He, Peizhao Zhang, Kan Chen, Peter Vajda

- Reducing label annotations for training object detectors and achieving SoTA results in semi-supervised object detection [ICLR'21]
- Being applied to several Meta's products

Georgia Tech

Aug. 2018 - Present

Graduate Research Assistant

Advisor: Prof. Zsolt Kira

- Developing machine learning techniques under limited supervision (e.g., few-shot learning, semi-supervised learning, etc.) [ICLR'19, ICLR'21, CVPR'22, ECCV'22]
- Initiating a new research area focused on multi-agent collaborative perception [ICRA'20, CVPR'20, IROS'21]
- Investigating and benchmarking on continual learning [NeurIPSW'18]

National Taiwan University

July 2016 - July 2018

Research Assistant

Advisor: Prof. Yu-Chiang Frank Wang

- Applying generative ML models to address domain adaptation problems [CVPR'18, NeurIPS'18]
- Improving depth estimation accuracy with aid of semantic priors [CVPR'19]
- Investigating and benchmarking on few-shot classification [ICLR'19]

Selected Publications

- [1] J. Tian, X. Dai, C.-Y. Ma, Z. He, <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, Zsolt Kira. Trainable Projected Gradient Method for Robust Fine-Tuning, *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2023
- [2] <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, C.-Y. Ma, Z. He, Z. Kira. Polyhistor: Parameter-Efficient Multi-Task Adaptation for Dense Vision Tasks, *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2022
- [3] <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, C.-Y. Ma, X. Dai, J. Tian, P. Vajda, Z. He, Z. Kira. Open-set Semi-Supervised Object Detection, *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2022 (Oral)
- [4] Y.-C. Liu, C.-Y. Ma, Z. Kira. Unbiased Teacher v2: Semi-supervised Object Detection for Anchor-free and Anchor-based Detectors, *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2022
- [5] Y.-C. Liu, C.-Y. Ma, Z. He, C.-W. Kuo, K. Chen, P. Zhang, B. Wu, Z. Kira, P. Vajda. Unbiased Teacher for Semi-Supervised Object Detection, *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2021
- [6] N. Glaser, Y.-C. Liu, J. Tian, Z. Kira Overcoming Obstructions via Bandwidth-Limited Multi-Agent Spatial Handshaking, International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2021
- [7] J. Tian, Y.-C. Liu, N. Glaser, Y.-C. Hsu, Z. Kira. Posterior Re-calibration for Imbalanced Datasets, *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2020
- [8] Y.-C. Liu, J. Tian, N. Glaser, Z. Kira. When 2com: Multi-Agent Collaborative Perception via Communication Graph Grouping, *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2020
- [9] <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, J. Tian, C.-Y. Ma, N. Glaser, C.-W. Kuo, Z. Kira. Who2com: Collaborative Perception via Learnable Handshake communication, *International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)*, 2020
- [10] J. Tian, W. Chung, N. Glaser, <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, Z. Kira. UNO: Uncertainty-aware Noisy-Or Multimodal Fusion for Unanticipated Input Degradation, *International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)*, 2020
- [11] P.-Y. Chen*, A. Liu*, <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, Y.-C. F. Wang. Towards Scene Understanding: Unsupervised Monocular Depth Estimation with Semantic-aware Representation, *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2019 (Oral; * equal contributions)
- [12] W.-Y. Chen, <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, Z. Kira, Y.-C. F. Wang, J.-B. Huang. A Closer Look at Few-shot Classification, *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2019
- [13] A. Liu, Y.-C. Liu, Y.-Y Yeh, Y.-C. F. Wang. A Unified Feature Disentangler for Multi-Domain Image Translation and Manipulation, *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2018
- [14] Y.-C. Liu, Y.-Y Yeh, T.-C. Fu, S.-D. Wang, W.-C. Chiu, Y.-C. F. Wang. Detach and Adapt: Learning Cross-Domain Disentangled Deep Representation, *IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2018 (Spotlight)

- [15] J. Tian, W. Cheung, N. Glaser, <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, Z. Kira. UNO: Uncertainty-aware Noisy-Or Multimodal Fusion for Unanticipated Input Degradation, *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS Workshops)*, 2019
- [16] Y.C. Hsu, <u>Y.-C. Liu</u>, Z. Kira. Re-evaluating Continual Learning Scenarios: A Categorization and Case for Strong Baselines, *Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems Workshops*(NeurIPS Workshops), 2018

Academic Services